# **Shabbir Khan**

951-530-5909 ◆ Hyderabad, TS 500008 ◆ sshabbir@yahoo.com ◆ www.linkedin.com/in/shabbirkh

# SENIOR MANAGER OF SALES OPERATIONS

High-impact leader and established rainmaker with repeated success in growing revenue, improving processes and developing top-performing sales and customer success teams.

# Visionary Sales Strategist | Enterprise Sales Expert | Respected Mentor & Coach

Multitalented sales leader with unique ability to design and execute sales plans, identify new segment opportunities, as well as create best practices for customer relationship management (CRM) tools.

Experienced in growing an organization from startup stage to fully matured business operations. Handled a wide spectrum of activities for business growth - sales and marketing activities, developing business plans / marketing strategies, implementing and executing them in real time sales environments

Top-notch data analyst who can effectively communicate findings and use knowledge to build concrete business models. Collaborate with cross-functional teams to positively impact bottom-line.

- ◆ Account Management
- ◆ Strategic Business planning
- ◆ Customer Satisfaction
- ◆ P&L Responsibility

- ◆ Sales Prospecting, Forecasting & Closing
- ◆ Client Relationship Management
- ◆ Productivity and Efficiency Improvement ◆ Contract Negotiation
- ◆ Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- ◆ Business Intelligence
- ◆ Quality Management
- - ◆ Customer Success

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## SelectSys India Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, TS

2016-2019

Project 1: Remote Books - Market-leading provider of bookkeeping, payroll, accounting, and tax services

Project 2: Trend Micro - Global leader in enterprise data security and cybersecurity solutions for Home, businesses, data centres and cloud environments. Project 3: Policy Bachat - Online Insurance web aggregator for life and auto insurance.

#### Senior Manager of Sales & Operations

Worked directly with CEO and COO to develop and implement sales and marketing strategies to maximize visibility within budget. Heavily involved in the entire program life cycle of 3 projects, from creative development and sales strategy to program delivery. Structured \$18M in annual recurring revenue and \$10M in new business revenue, positioning company for 200%+ growth in 2 years. Recruited, developed and managed a team size of 250+ including Sales managers, Operations manager and Team Leaders.

- Transitioned project from US and established the first dedicated Sales Division, including compensation plans, incentive programs, lead generation programs, marketing strategies, and high-performing sales team.
- Crafted an updated pricing strategy to better align price with customers willingness to pay. Also executed and analyzed the efficacy of different promotions to determine customer price sensitivity
- Constructed revenue share models for strategic white labeled partnerships with CPA's and other accounting/bookkeeping firms.
- Developed and then implemented Customer Success Strategy to determine how to increase retention and revenue from client base.
- Improved client engagement with our product and services through Client Portal, Product and Market research.
- Improved client retention by working directly with clients, support team, and other teams throughout the business to identify drivers of churn and improve the quality of service provided.
- Built dashboards to report on and provide insights on client and revenue retention and expansion related initiatives.
- Built and owned financial models, workforce planning, compensation strategy, operating metrics, weekly reporting, dashboards and more.

- Structured the analysis required to solve complex problems, and led analysts to execute it.
- ◆ Diagnosed complex problems and develop compelling recommendations that optimize bookkeeping operation to improve client retention and bookkeeping efficiency.
- Conducted research to guide product decisions and help shape our roadmap, working creatively with data to produce insights that drive product direction.
- Established partnerships with industry leaders to provide full scope of tools required to provide clients with a robust layered security.
- ◆ Worked with Trend Micro in Establishing and launching joint marketing strategy including monthly newsletters, cyber security webinars etc. for their Worry-free MSP model.
- Built and developed sales strategies for MSP model.
- Oversee and manage all sales activities from prospecting through close.
- ◆ Led and set directions for the Operations Strategy team.
- Created measures and analyzed KPI's that evaluated the technical quality of the bookkeeping team, the efficient use of time and the quality/accuracy of books
  - ➤ Time management
  - ▶ People Management Goals and Objectives and performance reviews.
  - SLA Compliance.
- Performance review with the customer.
- Demonstrated an ability to set the vision, direction, and culture of the team by managing individual and team performance, monitoring real time service levels and schedule adherence, and holding the team accountable for meeting and exceeding performance targets
  - Quality
  - ▶ VOC
  - Customer Satisfaction
  - First Call Resolution
- Managed the overall shrinkage, schedules and maintaining the highest level of service standards
- ◆ Participated in business leadership meetings, representing customer support business unit to CEO and COO level management.
- Managed the career growth and development of the Support team by driving focus on Leadership.
- Managed workflow, handled escalations, proactively engaged resources to address issues and effectively delegated workload across the leadership team.
- Drive creation of staffing plans, schedules, quality initiatives, process change initiatives.
- ◆ Managed technical service-related operations, identifying potential problems, technical gaps, and other obstacles.
- Conducted regular one-on-ones with direct reports to review individual performance and their team's performance, offer on-going augmentative support when required. Created a positive work environment through employee engagement; resolved employee relation issues in a professional and timely manner.
- Responsible to introduce many new tools in Online space to increase the inbound call flow, this helped the overall Average Order Value of the company to grow
- ◆ Participate in cross functional meetings to review information received from operational support functions Training, HR, Quality, WFM, and partner to define action plans that resolve issues and drive continuous improvement.

# **Shabbir Khan**

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED, Consultant

## **Independent Consultant** (2014–2016)

Work as part of a team to monitor clients existing business practices, identify weaknesses and recommend options and solutions for them. Counselled individuals and start-up ventures in developing strategic marketing plans based upon their needs. Developing and writing robust business plans.

- Developing and writing robust business plans.
- Identify any business expansion opportunities and provide solutions/action plans
- Identify cost saving mechanisms to change the revenue cost to the organization.
- Consultation also included website development, branding, planning investments in marketing and ROI
- Providing input to support the development of business road map and monthly/annual budgets.
- Proactively seeking out new business opportunities and cobrand partners.
- Developing and utilizing initiative to identify new merchant partners, payment gateways and marketing partners.
- Working within a team to manage the budget and achieve assigned targets.
- Report out any major outages within the business and report Root cause analysis
- Responsible for identifying process breaks, training needs and mentoring the team leads for handling operations.
- Analyzing data, numbers and information.
- Maintaining up-to-date market knowledge.
- Ensuring excellent customer service delivery at all times.
- Delivering business change.
- Shaping initiatives through idea generation and also developing proposals.
- Organizing and attending meetings with prospective clients or businesses.
- Providing clear, timely and effective management information to senior managers.

#### Bellovista Technologies, Kolkata, WB

March 2014- Nov 2014

Project: Trend Micro - Global leader in enterprise data security and cybersecurity solutions for Home, businesses, data centres and cloud environments.

## **Senior Manager - Sales Operations**

Worked as Senior Manager for Sales & Remote desktop support (Trend Micro). Role entails Performance Management, People Management, and Process Management. Relationship Management with Clients and partner companies and building on Brand through my role.

- Reporting of 1 Sales Manager and 3 Assistant Managers as a direct span.
- Proficient in managing & leading teams for running successful service delivery & process operations and experience of implementing procedures, service standards for business excellence.
- Review operation statistics to measure staff performance and the need for improvement
- Perform quality checks, develop and review performance reports, identify areas to improve, and implement measures to improve performance levels and meet objectives.
- Successfully met process critical service deliverables.
- Created Problem Management Process for Remote Support Team Knowledge Base Usage, Documentation and Incident Feedback Process.
- Implemented customer feedback system to avoid refund and chargeback.
- Played a key role in conceptualizing & developing in house applications & inter/intra departmental utilities, Refund, Chargeback process, call back Process and managing Process Level Email functions

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED, RIM

### Infinite Computer Solutions, Bangalore, KA

Jan 2011- Nov 2012

Next-Gen Business Technology Platformization and Product Engineering Services.

Project: iYogi RIM – Worlds most loved independent support brand, providing support to consumers & small businesses.

## Team Manager (RIM)

Team Manager for Sales and Remote Support Team of 40 members – Provided Technical support on Network, Applications, Web, Printers and Remote Office Support for iYogi customers. Mentored and managed all Team Members – Goal Setting, Training plan, Scheduling, Rewards and Recognition.

- Main point of contact for customers for escalation on Compliance. Ensure that Team understands the hidden expectation of the customers.
- ◆ Started a Pilot with 20 members and helped management to ramp up the process to 200+
- Identify relevant training needs & ensure effective implementation
- Strategizing the ramp up and ensuring smooth transition of resources into the system.
- Primary focus on driving revenue growth, increasing profit, exceeding service levels, organization development and managing risk compliance and change.
- Steering efforts in improving the operational systems, processes and policies in support of organizations mission
- Working closely with top management to draft and enforce Key Operations related procedure and policies within the organization
- ♦ Responsible for maintaining highest level of CSAT score of >90% month on month in tech support
- Recognized for new initiatives on exceeding the revenue targets while maintaining the customer satisfaction levels for the unit above 90%
- ◆ Developed Quality frame work, which was embedded back at customer and other vendor sites
- Constantly monitor & review performance metrics for achievement of objective

#### E4E (Now Concentrix), Bangalore, KA

July 2010- Dec 2010

An American business services company and a subsidiary of SYNNEX Corporation.

Project: iYogi RIM - Worlds most loved independent support brand, providing support to consumers & small businesses

#### Floor Tech Lead

Hired for training and managing transition teams of 15 new members.

- ◆ Conduct group training sessions on products and services
- ◆ Designed and implemented courses to train new employees on sales, Technical support and customer service
- Create additional training to address the challenges
- Briefed top level management on status of training program and future plans
- Collaborated with the HR department to implement a more strategic and effective hiring process

#### **Additional Experience**

Employer: Aditya Birla Minacs (Now Concentrix), Bangalore, KA

Project: Apple

Designation: Apple Care Specialist

Employer: HSBC Data Processing, Hyderabad, TS

Project: HBME RCC

Designation: Customer Care Representative

Employer: GE Country Wide Financials

Project: JC Penney

Designation: Customer Care Representative

# **Shabbir Khan**

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Commerce, Osmania University, Hyderabad, TS

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Technical Skills**: Salesforce.com, Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word, Access, Outlook, PowerPoint), Apple IOS, CRM, ERP systems